Every journey begins with a single move.
Searching for Bobby Fischer is a drama film directed by Steven Zaillian.
A seven-year-old chess prodigy refuses to harden himself in order to
become a champion like the famous but unlikable Bobby Fischer.
Josh Waitzkin, played by Max Pomeranc.
Fred Waitzkin, played by Joe Mantegna.
Bonnie Waitzkin, played by Joan Allen.
Bruce Pandolfini, played by Ben Kingsley.
Vinnie, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Jonathan Poe, played by Michael Nirenberg.
Searching for Bobby Fischer, released in the United Kingdom as Innocent Moves, is a 1993
American drama film written and directed by Steven Zaillian in his directorial debut.
Starring Max Pomeranc in his film debut, Joe Mantegna, Joan Allen, Ben Kingsley, and Laurence Fishburne, it is based on the life of prodigy
chess player Joshua Waitzkin, played by Pomeranc, and adapted from the book of the same name by Joshua's father, Fred Waitzkin.
The film was nominated for Best Cinematography in the 66th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of new york city, chess,
hustler, child prodigy, chess champion.
The tone is emotional.